# 你看這隻羊 早上被我扛回來了 抬回來的
Have a look at this goat. I brought it back this morning, I carried it back.
# 它不願意回來哦
In fact, it didn't wanna come back.
# 被我抬回來啦
So I carried it on my shoulder.
# 它很喜歡吃這個
It likes the,
# 野胡椒的 野 野胡椒的那葉子哦
the leaves, the leaves of the wild, wild pepper very much.
# 像草它都不喜歡吃
But it doesn't like the elephant grass that much.
# 山薑子
Wild ginger
# 我們這邊叫做山薑子
We call it wild ginger here.
# 吃那個 這個像草 紅像草它都不喜歡吃
It doesn't, elephant grass, the red elephant grass, it doesn't like it.
# 可能這個味道比較香
I think it's because it smells better.
# 我去搞一點 搞點在它窩裡面
Let's fetch some, fetch some into its lair.
# 搞點在它窩裡面
Let's fetch some into its lair.
# 讓它今天晚上吃個夠
So that it can have a big feast tonight.
# 你看 這個西瓜 那麼大啦
Have a look at this watermelon! It's so big now.
# 放在這裡 長大了再來搞 現在還小
Leave it here. I'll pick it, when it becomes big. Now it's still small.
# 好多刺啊這裡
It's very spiky here.
# 你看 這個 山胡椒
Look! This is, wild pepper.
# 就要這個葉子
We just need the leaves.
# 這個就夠它吃啦 這個
This is enough for it, here.
# 我從這裡扔下去就好了
Throw it down from here, that's it.
# 這個
The branches,
# 那樹枝不要的
I don't need the branches.
# 把尾巴砍掉就OK了
Cut off the tail and then it's okay.
# 它明年還會長葉子的
The leaves will still be growing next year.
# 我對那個羊多好啊
You see how well I treat the goats?
# 搞了七八條下去
So I've got seven or eight here.
# 我也現在也下去了
I'm also heading down as well.
# 這個陡坡要小心點 鴨都叫了
This steep slope, be a bit more careful. The ducks are yelping.
# 今天都忘記餵鴨了
I forgot to feed the ducks today.
# 這裡很陡的哦
It's really steep here.
# 你看
Look!
# 砍了那麼一點
So I've chopped a tiny little bit here.
# 給它們吃 看它們吃不吃的完
I'll feed them and see if they can finish it.
# 你看 剛拿下來 可能比較陌生 不怎麼喜歡吃
Look! I've just taken it here. I think it's not something quite new to them. So they don't really like it.
# 好啦 聞到味道啦
Good! They can smell it now.
# 還有那麼多它們又不想吃 剛才搞了一點它們又馬上在搶
They don't wanna eat when they see so much here. Whey were fighting over it when there was just a little.
# 它們兩個想打架
They wanted to start a fight.
# 別打架哦
No fighting here, got it?
# 打架你們就完了
If you fight, game over.
# 你看這個羊 它有些沒有角有些有角的
Have a look at the goats. Some have the horns while some don't.
# 你看這個就是沒角 同樣是母的 竟然它就有角它就沒角 (註︰「竟然」這個概念沒有直接翻譯，唯有把感覺寫出來)
Look! This one has no horns. They're both female, but this one has the horns but this one doesn't, strange.
# 可能它一個跟老媽姓 一個跟老爸姓
Perhaps one takes the name from its mom, and the other from its dad.